Humane Borders records, 2000-2010 MS 471
University of Arizona
Humane Borders Collection 2000-2010
MS 471
Humane Borders
32 Linear Feet
This collection is comprised of the records of Humane Borders. Items include press material and administrative files. The bulk of the material consists of media files including news clippings and audiovisual recordings relating to the organization and its cause of reducing the number of deaths in the Arizona borderlands. The collection also includes correspondence, financial, legal, legislative and research materials as well as reports and schedules related to the operation of Humane Borders.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
None
Further accruals are expected.
Sanctuary Movement Trial papers (MS 362)
Robin Hoover papers (MS 468)
The following maps have been transferred to the Library where they are cataloged and identified as part of these records:
2000-2004 Cell coverage map and deaths
Pima, Yuma, Pinal, Cochise, Maricopa and Santa Cruz Surface Management Maps
Border Patrol Map 2001 Deaths by Type
2000-2004 Cumulative Deaths Map
Biographical Note
Humane Borders is a non-profit, faith-based organization dedicated to creating a humane and just border environment by reducing the number of migrant deaths in the desert and striving to change United States policy so that migration occurs safely through ports of entry. Reverend Robin Hoover, pastor of the First Christian Church in Tucson, Arizona, founded Humane Borders in June 2000. In 2001, Humane Borders established a network of water stations in the desert borderlands of Arizona. Permits and agreements are in place with government agencies and private property owners along the border for Humane Borders volunteers to create and maintain the water stations. Humane Borders has collaborated with other congregations, non-profit organizations like Coalición de Derechos Humanos and government stakeholders such as the Pima County Board of Supervisors.
This collection is organized in five series.
Series List
Series I: Media Files, 2000-2010
Subseries 1: News clippings, June 1, 2000-December 29, 2009
Subseries 2: Audiovisual interviews with media and control files, 1996-2011 (bulk 2001-2010)
Series II: Correspondence, 2000-2010
Subseries 1: Correspondence, 2000-2009
Subseries 2: Phone Messages, June 17, 2001-October 11, 2010
Series III: Administrative Files, 2000-2011
Subseries 1: Calendars, 2000-2009
Subseries 2: Dissertations, House and Senate Bills and Lawsuit Material, 2001-2006
Subseries 3: Events and Remarks, 2001-2009
Subseries 4: Financial Reports, 2001-2009
Subseries 5: Operation Files and Permits, 2000-2011
Subseries 6: Reports and Studies, 2000-2009
Subseries 7: Water Trip Reports, 2002-2009
Subseries 8: Water Trip Schedules, 2003-2009
Series IV: Awards, November 2001-February 2008
Series V: Maps and Oversized Material, 2000-2004
Papers, 2000-ongoing (bulk 2000-2010). This collection is comprised of the papers of Humane Borders. The bulk of the material relates to press coverage of the organization and its cause of reducing the number of migrant deaths in the Arizona borderlands. Press coverage is mostly in print article format with audiovisual interviews stored on compact discs. Also included are administrative documents covering the management of the organization. These documents include correspondence, schedules, financial reports, land use permits, promotional materials, event materials and research materials such as maps and reports on migrant deaths created by the United States Border Patrol and drafts of House and Senate bills that shape United States policy on immigration. Other reports, studies and dissertations pertaining to the border region are also included.
Humane Borders, Inc.; Desert survival -- Mexican-American Border Region.; Drinking water -- Mexican-American Border Region.; Human rights workers -- United States -- Arizona -- Tucson.; Immigration advocates -- United States -- Arizona -- Tucson.; Immigration issues in the United States.; Nonprofit organizations -- Arizona.; Nonprofit organizations -- Management.
Container List
- Series I: Media Files, 2000-2010
  This series is grouped into subseries by format with each subseries arranged in chronological order. It contains news clippings and audiovisual material pertaining to immigration issues in the Southwestern United States borderlands and Humane Borders.
  - Subseries 1: News clippings, June 1, 2000-December 29, 2009
    This subseries is arranged chronologically. It contains news, magazine, and opinion articles and interview transcripts pertaining to immigration issues in the Southwestern United States borderlands and Humane Borders.
    - AZ Daily Star, June 1, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Associated Press Unknown Source, August 1, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Christian Science Monitor, August 4, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Arizona Republic, August 10, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Arizona Daily Star, circa August 13, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Arizona Friends Service Committee, September 2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Arizona Republic, September 7, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Arizona Republic, September 7, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Arizona Republic, September 10, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Arizona Daily Star, September 27, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Dallas News, September 28, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - USA Today - State News, September 28, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Arizona Daily Star, October 2, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Tucson Citizen, October 3, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Arizona Daily Star, October 4, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - El Universal, October 3, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Green Valley News and Sun, October 4, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Arizona Daily Star, October 6, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Arizona Daily Star, October 12, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Arizona Daily Star, October 29, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Arizona Daily Star, October 30, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Arizona Daily Star, October 31, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Tucson Weekly, November 9, 2000 - November 15, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - LA Times, November 28, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - LA Times, December 19, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Tucson Weekly, December 21 - December 27, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Arizona Republic, December 27, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Dallas Morning News, December 31, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - UC Davis Migration News, January 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Arizona Daily Star, January 5, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Tucson Citizen, February 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - International Herald Tribune, February 3, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Washington Post, February 25, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Tucson Citizen, March 7, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - New York Times, March 18, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Arizona Daily Star, March 20, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Associated Press, March 20, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Tucson Citizen, March 27, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Albuquerque Journal, April 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Business Week Online, April 9, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Stopgatekeeper.org, April 30, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - The Disciple, May 2001 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Homeland Ministries, May 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - San Pedro News, May 21, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - El Imparcial, May 24, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - New York Times, May 24, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Arizona Republic, May 24, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - The Lubbock Avalanche-Journal, May 24, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - New York Times, May 25, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Arizona Daily Star, May 25, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - New York Times, May 25, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - New York Times, May 25, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Arizona Daily Star, May 25, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - New York Times, May 25, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Borderlines, May 26, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Arizona Daily Star, May 26, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Arizona Daily Star Associated Press, May 26, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Arizona Daily Star, May 26, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Arizona Daily Star, May 26, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Green Valley Neighbors Home Page, May 28, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - New York Times, May 28, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Arizona Daily Star, May 29, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - New York Times, May 29, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Arizona Daily Star, May 30, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Tucson Citizen, May 30, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Arizona Daily Star, May 30, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - El Imparcial, May 30, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Frontera, May 30, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - El Imparcial, May 31, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Tucson Citizen, May 31, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Arizona Daily Star, May 31, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Tucson Citizen, May 31, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Salt of the Earth, June 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - United Church News, June 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Green Valley News, June 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Tucson Citizen, June 2, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Tucson Citizen, June 2, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Migrant Press Clips, June 2, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Time, June 3, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Arizona Daily Star, June 3, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Time, June 3, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Time, June 3, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Arizona Daily Star, June 5, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Tucson Citizen, Supes OK Funds, June 6, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Tucson Citizen, Survivors Offered Jobs, June 6, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Arizona Daily Star, Hiker finds migrant’s body in Organ Pipe Monument, June 6, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - La Prensa, June 6, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Arizona Republic, June 6, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Arizona Daily Star, June 6, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Tucson Citizen, June 7, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - Tucson Citizen, June 7, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - Tucson Citizen, June 7, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - Tucson Citizen, June 7, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - Arizona Republic, June 8, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - Green Valley News, June 8, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - New York Times, June 10, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - LA Times, June 10, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Arizona Daily Star, June 10, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - El Universal, June 10, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - Time Magazine, June 11, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 100)
    - Tucson Citizen, June 11, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 101)
    - National Council of Churches, June 11, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 102)
    - Arizona Daily Star, June 11, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 103)
    - Time Magazine, June 11, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 104)
    - Washington Post, June 11, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 105)
    - Imperial Valley Press, June 12, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 106)
    - Arizona Daily Star, June 12, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 107)
    - Arizona Daily Star, June 12, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 108)
    - Ashville Global Report, June 14, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 109)
    - Ashville Global Report, June 14, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 110)
    - PBS - Lehrer News Hour Transcript, June 15, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 111)
    - Tucson Citizen, June 15, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 112)
    - Arizona Daily Star, June 16, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 113)
    - Arizona Republic, June 16, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 114)
    - Arizona Daily Star, June 16, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 115)
    - Tucson Citizen, June 18, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 116)
    - Arizona Daily Star, June 19, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 117)
    - Arizona Daily Star, June 19, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 118)
    - Arizona Daily Star, June 19, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 119)
    - Arizona Daily Star, June 20, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 120)
    - Arizona Daily Star, June 20, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 121)
    - Green Valley News, June 20, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 122)
    - Arizona Republic, June 20, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 123)
    - Latino Reporter, June 21, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 124)
    - Arizona Daily Star, June 22, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 125)
    - Arizona Daily Star, June 22, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 126)
    - Arizona Daily Star, June 23, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 127)
    - Arizona Daily Star, June 23, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 128)
    - Dallas Morning News, June 23, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 129)
    - LA Times, June 23, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 130)
    - La Prensa San Diego, June 29, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 131)
    - Arizona Daily Star, June 29, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 132)
    - Arizona Daily Star, June 29, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 133)
    - Tucson Citizen, June 29, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 134)
    - United Church News, July 2001 (Box 1, Folder 135)
    - The Desert Sun, July 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 136)
    - UC Davis Migration, July 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 137)
    - Dallas Morning News, July 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 138)
    - Borderlines, July 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 139)
    - Arizona Daily Star, July 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 140)
    - Lutheran Office for Government Affairs, July 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 141)
    - Arizona Daily Star, July 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 142)
    - Migrationint.com, July 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 143)
    - Hoover Press Release, July 3, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 144)
    - Arizona Daily Star, July 6, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 145)
    - BBC Mundo, July 6, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 146)
    - Arizona Daily Star, July 7, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 147)
    - Abilene Reporter, July 8, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 148)
    - Arizona Daily Star, July 11, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 149)
    - Arizona Daily Star, July 12, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 150)
    - Horizon, July 12, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 151)
    - Arizona Daily Star, July 14, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 152)
    - New York Times, July 15, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 153)
    - Tucson Citizen, July 17, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 154)
    - Arizona Daily Star, July 17, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 155)
    - Tucson Citizen, July 17, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 156)
    - Arizona Daily Star, July 18, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 157)
    - Disciples News, July 18, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 158)
    - Arizona Republic, July 19, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 159)
    - Arizona Daily Star, July 21, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 160)
    - The Guardian, July 21, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 161)
    - Arizona Republic, July 23, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 162)
    - Arizona Republic, July 23, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 163)
    - Green Valley News, July 25, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 164)
    - La Voz, July 25, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 165)
    - Concerned Women of America, July 25, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 166)
    - Arizona Daily Star, July 28, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 167)
    - Arizona Daily Star, July 28, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 168)
    - La Nacion, July 29, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 169)
    - Virtual Tucson Magazine Everyday, August 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 170)
    - LA Times, August 2, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 171)
    - Arizona Republic, August 3, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 172)
    - Arizona Daily Star, August 3, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 173)
    - Arizona Daily Star, August 3, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 174)
    - La Jornada, August 12, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 175)
    - Arizona Republic, August 19, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 176)
    - Arizona Daily Star, August 22, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 177)
    - Arizona Daily Star, August 22, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 178)
    - Arizona Daily Star, August 24, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 179)
    - Arizona Republic, August 25, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 180)
    - Arizona Republic, Dying to Work, August 26, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 181)
    - Arizona Republic, August 26, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 182)
    - Green Valley News, August 28, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 183)
    - Borderlines, September 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 184)
    - Tucson Citizen, Five Day Series, September 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 185)
    - Arizona Daily Star, September 2, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 186)
    - Arizona Daily Star, September 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 187)
    - Tucson Citizen, September 5, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 188)
    - Tucson Citizen, September 5, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 189)
    - Tucson Citizen, September 5, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 190)
    - Tucson Weekly, September 6, 2001 - September 12, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 191)
    - Tucson Citizen, Five Day Series, September 6, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 192)
    - Arizona Daily Star, September 6, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 193)
    - Arizona Daily Star, September 6, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 194)
    - Arizona Daily Star, September 8, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 195)
    - Arizona Daily Star, September 8, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 196)
    - Arizona Daily Star, September 9, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 197)
    - Tucson Citizen, September 12, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 198)
    - Tucson Citizen, September 12, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 199)
    - Arizona Daily Star, September 14, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 200)
    - Arizona Daily Star, September 14, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 201)
    - Arizona Daily Star, September 15, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 202)
    - Tucson Citizen, September 17, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 203)
    - Arizona Daily Star, September 18, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 204)
    - Arizona Republic, September 25, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 205)
    - Arizona Daily Star, September 30, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 206)
    - Viet Catholic News, October 6, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 207)
    - Arizona Daily Star, October 14, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 208)
    - La Vaz, October 17, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 209)
    - Tucson Citizen, October 19, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 210)
    - Green Valley News, October 24, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 211)
    - San Antonio Express-News, October 27, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 212)
    - Rolling Stone, September 18, 2001, October 9, 2001, December 8, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 213)
    - Methodist Legislative Letter, November 2001 (Box 1, Folder 214)
    - Legislative Hearing, November 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 215)
    - Board of Regents Hearing, November 29, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 216)
    - Elizabeth Bontragen, Goshen College, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 217)
    - Language of Intercultural Communication, Chrispin Thurlow, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 218)
    - ILW.com Immigration Daily, January 1, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 219)
    - LA Times, January 1, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 220)
    - Anthropologia XLIV, January 1, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 221)
    - Journal: Language and Intercultural Communications, January 1, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 222)
    - Arizona Daily Star, January 13, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 223)
    - People on the Move, No. 88-89, January 24, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 224)
    - ElImparcial.com, January 27, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 225)
    - ElImparcial.com, January 27, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 226)
    - Interhemespheric Resource Center, February 1, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 227)
    - La Jornada, February 1, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 228)
    - El Universal, February 3, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 229)
    - Tucson Citizen, February 4, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 230)
    - Imagen Paseo Del Norte, February 6, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 231)
    - Articolo, February 9, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 232)
    - Staten Island Advance, February 23, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 233)
    - Radio Onadas, February 24, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 234)
    - Westmoreland Congregational United Church of Christ, March 3, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 235)
    - Todito.com, March 4, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 236)
    - Arizona Daily Wildcat, March 6, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 237)
    - Arizona Daily Star, March 14, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 238)
    - Arizona Daily Star, March 14, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 239)
    - Tucson Citizen, March 15, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 240)
    - Tucson Citizen, March16, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 241)
    - Arizona Daily Star, March 16, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 242)
    - Tucson Citizen, March 16, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 243)
    - Arizona Daily Star, March 17, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 244)
    - Arizona Daily Star, March 16, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 245)
    - Tucson Citizen, March 19, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 246)
    - MSNBC, March 22, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 247)
    - Stanford.edu, March 23, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 248)
    - Tucson Citizen, March 23, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 249)
    - Tucson Citizen, March 23, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 250)
    - Tucson Citizen, March 25, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 251)
    - Republic, March 26, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 252)
    - IRS Exemption Rulings, March 26, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 253)
    - Arizona Daily Star, March 28, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 254)
    - Arizona Daily Star, March 28, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 255)
    - Arizona Daily Star, March 28, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 256)
    - Arizona Daily Star, March 31, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 257)
    - Good News Magazine, April 1, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 258)
    - Tucson Citizen, April 1, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 259)
    - Call to Justice, April 1, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 260)
    - Arizona Daily Star, April 2, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 261)
    - MSNBC, April 3, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 262)
    - El Diario, April 3, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 263)
    - Imagen, April 3, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 264)
    - Arizona Daily Star, April 3, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 265)
    - Tucson Citizen, April 4, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 266)
    - National Catholic Reporter, April 5, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 267)
    - National Catholic Reporter, April 5, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 268)
    - Arizona Daily Star, April 6, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 269)
    - Tucson Citizen, April 6, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 270)
    - Arizona Daily Star, April 8, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 271)
    - Tucson Citizen, April 10, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 272)
    - Arizona Daily Star, April 10, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 273)
    - News-Sun Benson, April 10, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 274)
    - Phoenix (NotiMex), April 2002 (Box 1, Folder 275)
    - Tucson Citizen, April 15, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 276)
    - Bohemio News, April 16, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 277)
    - Tucson Citizen, April 17, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 278)
    - Tucson Citizen, April 19, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 279)
    - Arizona Daily Star, Boy left in desert, April 20, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 280)
    - Green Valley News, April 24, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 281)
    - Central America/Mexico Report, May-June 2002 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Frontera Norte Sur, May 1, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - El Imparcial, May 1, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Arizona Daily Star, May 1, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Property Rights Research - Immigrants, May 8, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Arizona Daily Star, May 9, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Tucson Citizen, May 9, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Tucson Citizen, May 9, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Arizona Republic, May 9, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Tucson Citizen, May 9, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - New York Times, May 10, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Washington Times, May 11, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Arizona Daily Star, May 11, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Arizona Daily Star, May 11, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - LA Times, May 12, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - O’Reilly Show, May 13, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - KOLD-TV, May 14, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Arizona Republic, May 13, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - KVOA-TV, May 14, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Arizona Republic, May 14, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - La Jornada, May 15, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Arizona Daily Star, May 15, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Arizona Daily Star, May 15, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Tucson Citizen, May 16, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - MSNBC, May 18, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Arizona Republic, May 19, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Arizona Republic, May 19, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Arizona Republic, May 19, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Arizona Daily Star, May 20, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Arizona Daily Star, May 20, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Politically Incorrect, May 21, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - El Universal, May 22, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Frontera Hispana, May 22, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Arizona Daily Star, May 23, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - EFE News Service, May 23, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Frontera Norte Sur, May 24, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - The Tidings, May 24, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Tucson Citizen, May 24, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - RandomWalks.com, May 26, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Refuse and Resist, May 26, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 40)